Guide to the Mario Ancona Collection
Stanford Archive of Recorded Sound
- Sound Recordings
  - Arias and Lieder, disc: 33 1/3 rpm, vinyl; 12 in. (Box 11, Folder 5)
    Herrold. Limited EditionSide 1:Mascagni, Pietro, 1863-1945. Cavalleria rusticana. Viva il vino spumeggiante -- Donizetti, Gaetano, 1797-1848. Lucrezia Borgia. Segreto per esser felici -- Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Otello. Credo in un Dio crudel -- Flotow, Friedrich von, 1812-1883. Martha. Ach! so fromm, ach! so traut -- Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Liederkreis, op. 39. Frühlingsnacht -- Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Don Giovanni. Deh, vieni alla finestra -- Meyerbeer, Giacomo, 1791-1864. Robert le diable. -Robert, toi que j'aime -- Donizetti, Gaetano, 1797-1848. Favorite. Pour tant d'amour Side 2:Thomas, Ambroise, 1811-1896. Mignon. Je suis Titania -- Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Rienzi. Allmächt'ger Vater -- Saint-Saëns, Camille, 1835-1921. Samson et Dalila. Mon cur s'ouvre ta voix -- Hahn, Raynaldo, 1875-1947. Heure exquise -- Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Traviata. Addio del passato -- Rossini, Gioacchino, 1792-1868. Barbiere di Siviglia. Se il mio nome saper -- Bizet, Georges, 1838-1875. Carmen. Chanson du tor#&233;ador
  - Arias and Songs. Collector's Society. Christmas 1961, souvenir disc: 33 1/3 rpm, vinyl; 12 in. (Box 11, Folder 6)
    Side 1:Serrano & del Campo. Carmencita la gitana -- Bantock. Song of the seals -- Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847. Heimkehr aus der Fremde -- Weber, Carl Maria von, 1786-1826. Euryanthe. Glöcklein im Tale! Rieseln im Bach -- Rossini, Gioacchino, 1792-1868. Semiramide. Selection -- Dickinson & Phillips. Wimmen, Oh Wimmen -- Anon. Rosario de la Aurora -- Loewe, Carl, 1796-1869. Ballades, op. 1. Erlkönig.Side 2:Catalani. Dunque ei m' ama -- Nicolo. Romance joconde -- Vasseur. Bolero Grande -- Tost -- Tosti, F. Paolo (Francesco Paolo), 1846-1916. Serenata; Invano -- Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Traviata. Selection -- Mascagni, Pietro, 1863-1945. Maschere. Questa e una strada -- Henrion. Muletier de Tarragone -- Ruggi. Due Ciabbatini -- Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Trovatore. Deserto sulla terra
  - Bellini, Vincenzo, 1801-1835. Puritani. Ah per sempre io ti perdei, disc: 33 1/3 rpm, vinyl; 10 in. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Don Giovanni. Deh, vieni alla finestra, Test pressing: 78 rpm, shellac; 10 in. (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Don Giovanni. Deh, vieni alla finestra, disc: 78 rpm, shellac; 10 in. (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Tosti, F. Paolo (Francesco Paolo), 1846-1916. Mattinata, disc: 78 rpm, shellac; 10 in. (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Otello. Era la notte, disc: 33 1/3 rpm, vinyl; 10 in. (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Re di Lahore. O' casto fior and Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Traviata. Di Provenza il mar, disc: 78 rpm, shellac; 13 3/4 in. (Oversize 8, Folder 12)
  - Bellini, Vincenzo, 1801-1835. Puritani. Ah per sempre io ti perdei (duplicate), disc: 33 1/3 rpm, vinyl; 10 in. (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Bellini, Vincenzo, 1801-1835. Puritani. Ah per sempre io ti perdei (duplicate), disc: 33 1/3 rpm, vinyl; 10 in. (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Bellini, Vincenzo, 1801-1835. Puritani. Ah per sempre io ti perdei (duplicate), disc: 33 1/3 rpm, vinyl; 10 in. (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Bizet, Georges, 1838-1875. Carmen. Chanson du tor#&233;ador, disc: 33 1/3 rpm, vinyl; 10 in. (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Otello. Era la notte (duplicate), disc: 33 1/3 rpm, vinyl; 10 in. (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Otello. Era la notte (duplicate), disc: 33 1/3 rpm, vinyl; 10 in. (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Otello. Era la notte (duplicate), disc: 33 1/3 rpm, vinyl; 10 in. (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Otello. Era la notte (duplicate), disc: 33 1/3 rpm, vinyl; 10 in. (Box 11, Folder 19)
- Miscellany
  - Giacomo Ancona binder notes and documents I (Box 12, Folder 1)
    Lists documenting the Mario Ancona collection.
  - Giacomo Ancona's binder notes and documents II (Box 12, Folder 2)
    Biography of Mario Ancona; Reviews; Translations of Leoncavallo's letters; Opera casts 1893-1904; Opera announcements; Fees received by Mario Ancona; Metropolitan Opera programs, casts (in house) 1893 - 1897; Metropolitan Opera tours and casts 1893 - 1897; Teatro National de San Carlos 1897 - 1912
  - Giacomo Ancona's binder notes and documents III (Box 12, Folder 3)
    Reviews; Discographies
  - Handmade box entitled publications (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Giacomo Ancona's discography notes (Box 12, Folder 4)